Skyler Schuck

skyler.schuck@colostate.edu | skylerschuck.github.io | linkedin.com/in/skyler-schuck/

About Me

Experience in information technology, data science, and applied economic analysis. A seasoned user in R, SQL, and Python. My research interests include regional analysis and improving rural outcomes. Most of my projects are centered around creating data/information systems and tools to support my research.

Education

2021 – Present	M.S., Agricultural and Resource Economics, Colorado State University Anticipated graduation in Spring 2023, GPA: 3.8
2017 - 2021	B.A., Economics, <i>California Lutheran University</i> Magna Cum Laude, GPA: 3.8
2017 - 2021	B.S., Computer Information Systems, <i>California Lutheran University</i> Magna Cum Laude, GPA: 3.8

Professional Experience

Thousand Oaks, CA

Professional Experience			
05/2022 – present Denver, CO	Technology Intern, <i>Transamerica</i> Working within Life Technology in Technology Services, I work on data and API engineering projects using AWS(API Gateway, Lambda, DynamoDB, etc.) for maintenance and feature creation for the Financial Services Agent's web portal.		
01/2022 – Present Denver, CO	Data Science Intern, City and County of Denver Housed within the Department of Finance, major duties include generating economic analysis, forecasts, and reports for internal and external uses. Internal reports include economic outlook and forecast presentations to the City Council and the Mayor. External facing work includes creating economic indicator dashboards. Daily tasks also include data cleaning, visualization generation, and general consulting with other departments within the city.		

08/2021 – Present	Graduate Research Assistant, Colorado State Univesity
Fort Collins, CO	Apart of the Regional Economic Development Institute (F

Apart of the Regional Economic Development Institute (REDI) at CSU. Generate regional economic analysis for on-going projects and as-needed when requested by City/County/State Agencies. Leading website re-design project for more interactive and engaging experience.

03/2021 - 07/2021 **IT Specialist,** *River Oaks Academy* Westlake Village, CA

Provided all operational technology support of the Charter School across two campuses including: Computer tech support and maintenance, Student registration: system support and use, Software and hardware support: troubleshooting and installation, GSuite Administration, Website and social media management, Network management (Cisco Meraki), Photo, video &

sound editing (Adobe CC). 01/2018 - 04/2021

IT Technician (Student), California Lutheran University Faced the full spectrum of technological challenges at the University, ranging from helping professors in their laboratories and offices as well as providing classroom technology support. This meant quickly assessing challenges, and offering technology solutions in a broad range of time-sensitive situations. Furthermore, given the fluid population and needs of the University, constantly bonding well with new team members and quickly adapting and integrating new skills.

Publications

12/2021

Fishers Peak State Park: Evaluating a New Natural Amenity in Southern Colorado,

REDI@CSU ☑

The recently christened Fishers Peak State Park offers great potential to give a much-needed

boost to the economy of Las Animas County, specifically the town of Trinidad.

Skills

R Shiny, tidyverse	••••	Python Pandas, Pystat	• • • • •
AWS API Gateway, Lambda, DynamoDB	••••	Dashboarding Power BI, Tableau, AWS Athena	• • • • •
Web Development HTML/CSS/JS	• • • • •		

Courses

Applied Microeconomic Theory, Colorado State University

Applied Econometrics, Colorado State University

Quantitative Methods, Colorado State University

Applied Welfare and Policy Analysis, Colorado State University

Environmental and Natural Resource Economics, *Colorado State University*

Applied Advanced Water Resource Economics, *Colorado State University*

Database Management Systems, *California Lutheran University*

Software Engineering, California Lutheran University

Systems Analysis, California Lutheran University

Information, Systems, and Organizational Design, California Lutheran University

Data Analysis with R, California Lutheran University